

63

Contact

Email: utejoe.ju@gmail.com Phone: +2347057816536

Address: Lagos, Nigeria

Portfolio: <u>Uyiobazeeportfolio</u>

Github: Utejoe

LinkedIn: Uyi Obazee



Education

- University of BeninB.Eng Civil EngineeringCompleted in 2022
- Africa Leadership Experience
 Certificate in Software Engineering
 Completed in 2023

H Technical Skills

- Programming Languages
- Software Development
- Database Management Systems
- Tools
- Website Creation
- Development on Linux Systems
- Devops
- · Version Control: Git, Github
- Mobile app development: (In Progress)

UYI OBAZEE

SOFTWAREENGINEER

Profile

Experienced Full-Stack Software Engineer with 3 years of experience. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, PHP, Wordpress, Python, Git, MySQL, Linux, and Bash scripting, software development methodologies, and database management systems. Strong problem-solving skills and ability to work effectively in a teambased environment. Currently exploring Laravel and React Native.

Work Experience

Nov 2023 - Present

BEMA Integrated service | Lekki, Lagos State

Full-Stack Software Developer

- Built the Backend and part of the frontend development of a music website using PHP, WordPress, JavaScript, Python, HTML, and CSS.
- Established synchronization among our website database, an Ecommerce platform, and Mailerlite for our CRM by developing a custom WordPress plugin utilizing PHP and REST API.
- Integrated Wavesurfer library for interactive audio visualization in the website's footer
- Established seamless connections to Easy Digital Downloads for efficient music transactions.
- Integrated MailerLite API to facilitate seamless newsletter communication with users, enhancing the efficiency of email marketing processes.
- Onsite presence, actively engaged in ongoing development and maintenance for optimal functionality and user satisfaction.

Sep 2023 - Oct 2023

J. P. Morgan's Forage

Software Engineer

- Built the Backend and part of the frontend development of a music website using PHP, WordPress, JavaScript, Python, HTML, and CSS.
- Established synchronization among our website database, an Ecommerce platform, and Mailerlite for our CRM by developing a custom WordPress plugin utilizing PHP and REST API.
- Integrated Wavesurfer library for interactive audio visualization in the website's footer.
- Established seamless connections to Easy Digital Downloads for efficient music transactions.
- Integrated MailerLite API to facilitate seamless newsletter communication with users, enhancing the efficiency of email marketing processes.
- Onsite presence, actively engaged in ongoing development and maintenance for optimal functionality and user satisfaction.

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Problem–Solving
- Teamwork
- Adaptability
- Time Management
- · Attention to Detail
- Creativity
- Customer Focus

Aug 2022 - sept 2023

ALX Africa

Software Engineer

- Engaged in a rigorous curriculum covering advanced topics in software development, including data structures, algorithms, and design patterns.
- Collaborated with a diverse team of fellow interns on complex projects, simulating real world development environments.
- Developed and deployed multiple full-stack web applications, showcasing proficiency in technologies such as JavaScript, Python, HTML/CSS, and SQL, making use of Linuxbased systems for development and deployment.
- Actively participated in code reviews and provided constructive feedback to peers, fostering a culture of collaboration and continuous improvement.
- Successfully completed an intensive software engineering program with a focus on practical, hands-on projects. Devoted an average of 70 hours per week to coursework.

Feb 2021 - Sept 2023

Code Base

MERN Stack Developer

- Engaged in hybrid work, supporting MERN stack app development.
- · Collaborated on feature implementation, bug fixes, and optimization.
- Embraced agile methodologies and contributed to code reviews for team cohesion.

Projects

Bemamusic

This is a music website built with WordPress, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Ajax/jQuery, and REST API. I worked on the player button functionality using JavaScript. Additionally, I developed a custom plugin named Bema CRM to synchronize data between the CRM database, MailerLite, and the Easy Digital Download platform, ensuring seamless user data monitoring. A payment gateway was also integrated using PayPal and it works fine.

Judysphere

Is a Social Media App, I created the complete website using the MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) stack. Employed version control with Git and GitHub to keep it up to date. Judysphere allows users to connect. Users can register, connect with other users, and share messages.

Portfolio

All other projects are found in my <u>portfolio website</u>. This website is constantly updated using Git and Github.

Reference

Engr. Nowamagbe Ogbeifun

MNSE, COREN Reg. NIHTE, MNICE

Phone: +2347038645748

Email: nowamagbe.ogbeifun@uniben.edu